<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-06-30T23:05:08+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Radio System Design</title><subtitle>Radio System Design is an RF and Microwave consultancy with over 40 years of experience</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Web SDR</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2025/06/25/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Web SDR" /><published>2025-06-25T03:51:37+01:00</published><updated>2025-06-25T03:51:37+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2025/06/25/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2025/06/25/welcome-to-jekyll.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="getting-started-with-sdr"><strong>Getting Started with SDR</strong></h1>

<p>If you are just interested in SDR then you can find out more from our free guide.</p>

<p>Or to learn more download the guide and a Ubuntu live distribution with all the 
software and files used in the presentation from this free software link. (See also paragraph below)</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/KiwiSDRControl.png" alt="Image description" style="float: right; margin-right: 1em; max-width: 30%" />
You don’t even need a radio or any software because, enthusiasts around the world 
have generously installed SDRs and made them available on the web.  All you need 
is an internet connection, a web browser and some help to get started.</p>

<p>The guide is a presentation to show you the basics.  Essentially your web connection allows you to listen in and control an SRD remotely and the guide show you:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Examples of web SDRs and where you can find others</li>
  <li>How to control kiwiSDR, which is one of the most common</li>
  <li>How to record IQ data for further processing</li>
  <li>Examples of processing recorded signals using GNU Radio</li>
  <li>Some of the dedicated decoders available via web SDRs</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started with SDR]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Radios are Everywhere</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2024/06/25/Everywhere.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Radios are Everywhere" /><published>2024-06-25T03:51:37+01:00</published><updated>2024-06-25T03:51:37+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2024/06/25/Everywhere</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2024/06/25/Everywhere.html"><![CDATA[<p>Radio signals are used in a huge variety of applications.  In fact the radio spectrum, 
which starts at only 500kHz extends to almost 500 GHz and is completley filled with 
different services.  Things from submarine to satellite communications; mobile phone 
to wireless broadcasts, clothing tabs to aircraft navigation, all use the radio 
spectrum.  We use these services every day, maybe without fully realising the challenges 
that are overcome to deliver them.</p>

<p>Also, in recent year the advent of digital technology has triggered a revolution in the 
design of radio systems, opening up new posssibilities for cooperation, communications 
and control in an even wider range of applicaitons. So if you think that radio systems 
is an established technology, think again.  It has in fact never been more dynamic and 
revolutionary.  It is the key in much of the technological innovation that is driving 
the modern economy and the experienced staff at RSD have lived through and gained 
experience from this tremendous revolution.</p>

<p>Consider that the number of radio receivers and particularly transmitters has mushroomed 
in recent years.  Forty years ago most people owned a few radio recievers and only 
governements and big organisations used transmitters.  In contrast, today most people 
own more than 10 transmitters and receivers each.  If that seems an exageration, take a 
moment to think about it.  Remember, not just the 1 or 2 traditional broadcast radio and 
television receivers in the house; it includes phones, WiFi and bluetooth as well. There 
are radios are in cars, there are 2 or 3 in each mobile phone as well as each wireless 
router,  laptop computer and tablet. Then consider the ever growing number of ‘things’<br />
that now include radio connectivity,  digital assistants, streaming audio devices, car 
and home security systems, luggage labels, watches. and more; your pet may even have one! 
If you have been counting your devices, 10 is almost certainly an underestimate!</p>

<p>© 2025 radiosystemdesign.com</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Radio signals are used in a huge variety of applications. In fact the radio spectrum, which starts at only 500kHz extends to almost 500 GHz and is completley filled with different services. Things from submarine to satellite communications; mobile phone to wireless broadcasts, clothing tabs to aircraft navigation, all use the radio spectrum. We use these services every day, maybe without fully realising the challenges that are overcome to deliver them.]]></summary></entry></feed>